Alan A. Andrusky

Full Stack Software Developer

Phone (814) 823-2484

E-mail alanandrusky@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/alanandrusky
Portfolio alanandrusky.com
Github github.com/aandrusky

Education Skills

09/2020 - Current

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Web Development, Nashville, TN

08/2010 - 05/2014

Edinboro University of Pennsylvania

BBA- Marketing, PA

01/2012 - 12/2012

Belmont University

Music Business, Nashville, TN

HTML

Django

• (SS

• (¬i

JavaScript

• Agile

React

Scrum

Python

SQL

About me

Account Executive turned full stack software engineer. I spent 6 years immersed in technology; started selling directly to consumers, and then ultimately to public sector organizations and private enterprise customers. After learning the landscape, I found myself wanting to dive deeper into the product, and so began my career change journey into software development.

Developer Experience

09/2020 - Current

Full Stack Software Developer- Apprentice

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN

Intensive full-time 6-month software development program creating applications individually and in team-based projects in a Linux environment.

- Worked in remote environment utilizing Slack and Zoom
- Built single page applications with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Bootstrap
- Learned functional React including hooks and styling with React-Bootstrap
- Git and Github for version control
- Tech Stack: Python/ Django; React.js; JavaScript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL fundamentals

Projects:

Bourbon Log | Individual project | See Github here

Bourbon Log is a single page, data-driven application for bourbon lovers who seek to simplify the way the track their tasting notes. It eliminates the disparate notes across notebooks, napkins and phones, and consolidates them into a fun, easy to use format where their notes are accessible and meaningful.

- Built with React, React-Bootstrap, and React-chartsis-2
- Full CRUD functionality using JS Fetch API

Holiday Road | Group project | See Github here

This application creates a travel itinerary for an end-user. The local 7-day forecast renders simultaneously with the selected park based on matching their longitude and latitude coordinates in the APIs. This was accomplished with the use of local and remote API's to perform asynchronous fetch calls to pull national park data, national eatery/attractions data, and local weather data. Then dispatching the selection click and change events by using event hubs for decoupling.

- Vanilla Javascript application built in a Scrum framework
- Performed daily stand-ups to review each sprint
- Concluded project with a demonstration and retrospective

Professional Experience

07/2019 - 02/2020

Enterprise Account Executive

Box Inc., Nashville, TN

- Built relationships in commercial, greenfield territories with senior levels of leadership across multiple lines of businesses
- Led Account strategy across support engineers and internal reps in developing engagement and execution plans for driving net-new business
- Understood customers' core business goals to teach value in Box Saas products while competing and collaborating with tools from the likes of Microsoft and Google
- Used Box platform for team and customer deliverables, sales cycle management, and version control

08/2017 - 07/2019

Account Executive - Public K12 & Higher Education

SHI International Corp., Nashville, TN

- Delivered profitable field sales through lead generation and management of sales of products and services:
- Developed and implemented sales plans and strategies to maximize revenue growth by building strong, long term business relations with customers, partners and vendors
- Negotiated, planned, and executed exclusive purchasing contracts with largest public school districts and universities in TN
- Offered in-depth customer technology solutions across a wide variety of IT products through customer trainings
- Successfully increased territory revenue by 12.13% and increased gross margin by 43.01% since hired
- Used Microsoft Dynamics for CRM and Sharepoint for contracts management

11/2016 - 03/2017

Treatment Consultant

American Addiction Centers, Brentwood, TN

- Developed and implemented all aspects of sales and marketing brand development strategies
- Directly worked with clients and established profitable relationship handling clinical treatment sales for medical care industry
- Ensured standards for quality, customer service, and sales are met
- Provided clients with guidance on federal regulation, insurance terms, and available treatment options

12/2014 - 11/2016

Inside Sales Representative

Dell Technologies, Nashville, TN

- Responsible for growing sales within 150+ accounts across Washington DC, DE, and MD
- Consistently exceeded annual quotas of \$6M+
- VMware VSP Certified
- Piloted, trained, and assisted in development of new order processing tool
- Grew team utilization of new order processing tool from 16% to 61% in 3 weeks
- Organized Culture Committee events/ created media for organization of 200+ personnel
- Mentored for new hire groups
- Certified by Dell in selling skills and product/services knowledge
- Proficient in Salesforce, Office Suite, and SharePoint

07/2013 - 12/2014

Sales Consultant

Best Buy, Erie, PA & Nashville, TN

- Consistently exceeded attach rate goals by >15%
- Consistently exceeded services attach rate by >25%
- Attended funded off-site 3-day sales training
- Led team in targeted mobile plan activation (71% vs. team avg. 41%)